hey guys coach Brett contras here this
is going to be a video that shows you
how to do quadruped light swings now uh
I have a a bench here this is pretty
tall cuz I'm tall the ladies and shorter
guys might be able to get away with a
shorter bench but um
basically it's like quadruped hip
extensions with more of a straight leg
but I'm going to do them
rapidly and um I keep my knee angle
fixed so it's not it's not changing as I
as I extend the hips but you can do this
three different ways so I can go
straight back like
this I can go out to the side I can go
kind of at an angle so one cool thing is
to just uh just rotate them and go out
angle back out angle
[Applause]
back once you feel like you might feel
the upper glutes fatigue you might be
able to crank out a few just regular
quadraped now some things to look for
see my low
back my lumbar spine will extend a
little bit and my pelvis will rotate a
little bit you can see so watch this
area here you'll see it moving a little
a little bit but it's not that much it's
controlled I'm not
like so you want to some people that
helps them to keep the core tight brace
the ABS I personally don't do that I
just try to think squeeze glutes so a
little bit of motion is fine just not
too much so watch that and try to make
the movement through the hips mostly
through glute squeeze limit the amount
of lumbo pelvic
motion so once again I'm going to show
you I'm going switch legs and show you a
set of 10 and you can do it any way you
want you could do all your reps this way
and then all your reps this way and then
all your reps this way or you can rotate
them there's different ways to do it you
can also eliminate the angled one and
just go out so it could look like
this
one
3 4
9 10 so that produces a pretty good burn
just with body weight but my leg is
longer and weighs more than most people
so I'm going to get more hip torque than
most people because I weigh a lot and
I'm tall if you're a smaller woman
body weight might not be challenging
enough for you so you can use ankle
weights here now this is a 20 lb ankle
weight but it's really hard for me to do
it things to watch out for you need to
get this super tight there can't be any
moving
around so I get this really tight on my
leg because it'll flop
around but what you want to do is you
don't it's really hard hard because when
you have weight here now the hamstring
has to work to control you know the
amount of knee flexion and you want the
tension to stay on the glutes so most
people would be fine with like a 5 lb
weight starting out but body weight
might also be fine for people but watch
how I do this I'm going to try and not
if I do it poorly I'm going to like
fling and you can see my leg just kind
of going everywhere I'm going to try and
keep this control knee angle and just
squeeze at the
glutes like
that and even then I can feel a little
bit
of uh it's kind of hard to control but
you can get it to feel right so this
works very well and if you want to
rotate
out now when you have ankle weads you
might be limited in what but you can do
outwards you might be a lot stronger
with hip extension compared to hip
transverse
abduction another thing that sometimes
you'll feel the glutes on this hip
working while you're working the other
side cuz it's working to stabilize you
so kind of you might have to rest a
little bit in between when you switch
sides now the last way I'm going to show
you this is kind of a different movement
but you can also do with this with bands
and you might not need a bench for this
I use a bench but it might not be needed
but I'm going to show you with a band
here so I'm just going to put this
middle of my foot and what I do here is
I'm get back now this is hard cuz my leg
wants to snap back but I'm going to get
up here like this I'm going to have the
bands go
in this is really hard see now the band
goes in between my knees like that so
now I stabilize I want to get a nice
stable base and then kick back and
squeeze that
glute so you can get it just
right but
it's kind of hard you got to get the
right distance that challenges end range
hip extension but this isn't more of a
swing this is more of a kickback the
others is more of an arcing swinging
motion but anyway I like throwing this
in at the either at the beginning of a
workout to activate the glutes or at the
end of a workout just to burn them
out once again quadri ped leg swings
they're good to do with just body weight
for high WS you can add ankle weights or
do the kickback with the band I hope you
enjoy the video